[
    {
        "question": "Which organization collaborated with NASA's ICESat-2 to create the first undersea map of the submerged ‘Ram Setu’?",
        "options": [
            "Geological Survey of India (GSI)",
            "National Institute of Oceanography (NIO)",
            "Indian Space Research Organisation (ISRO)",
            "Archaeological Survey of India (ASI)"
        ],
        "answer": "Indian Space Research Organisation (ISRO)"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where was India’s first World Peace Centre inaugurated?",
        "options": [
            "New Delhi",
            "Mumbai",
            "Gurugram, Haryana",
            "Varanasi"
        ],
        "answer": "Gurugram, Haryana"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which organization established India’s first World Peace Center?",
        "options": [
            "Bharatiya Vidya Bhavan",
            "Ramakrishna Mission",
            "Ahimsa Vishwa Bharti",
            "Art of Living Foundation"
        ],
        "answer": "Ahimsa Vishwa Bharti"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which former President of India attended the inauguration of the first World Peace Center?",
        "options": [
            "Pratibha Patil",
            "APJ Abdul Kalam",
            "Ram Nath Kovind",
            "K. R. Narayanan"
        ],
        "answer": "Ram Nath Kovind"
    },
    {
        "question": "What global platforms is India’s first World Peace Center expected to amplify India's voice on?",
        "options": [
            "World Economic Forum and G20.",
            "United Nations (UN) and World Parliament of Religions.",
            "International Monetary Fund and World Bank.",
            "Olympics and FIFA."
        ],
        "answer": "United Nations (UN) and World Parliament of Religions."
    },
    {
        "question": "Where are the Khelo India Winter Games 2025 scheduled to be held?",
        "options": [
            "Shimla",
            "Manali",
            "Gulmarg, Jammu and Kashmir",
            "Auli"
        ],
        "answer": "Gulmarg, Jammu and Kashmir"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where is the Hockey India League 2024-25 scheduled to be held?",
        "options": [
            "Kalinga Stadium, Bhubaneswar",
            "Major Dhyan Chand National Stadium, Delhi",
            "Birsa Munda Hockey Stadium, Rourkela",
            "M. A. Chidambaram Stadium, Chennai"
        ],
        "answer": "Birsa Munda Hockey Stadium, Rourkela"
    },
    {
        "question": "On December 6, which festival, inaugurated by the Prime Minister, showcased Northeast India's arts, crafts, and traditions?",
        "options": [
            "Rashtriya Kala Utsav",
            "Bharat Shilp Mahotsav",
            "Northeast Heritage Festival",
            "Ashtalakshmi Mahotsav",
            "None of the Above"
        ],
        "answer": "4"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the purpose of the MoU to be signed between the National Minorities Development and Finance Corporation (NMDFC) and the Dalit Indian Chamber of Commerce and Industry (DICCI)?",
        "options": [
            "To promote digital literacy among marginalized communities",
            "To empower marginalized communities through entrepreneurship",
            "To provide financial aid for education",
            "To support healthcare initiatives for marginalized groups",
            "None of the Above"
        ],
        "answer": "2"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which department is developing the National Legal Metrology Portal (eMaap) to centralize legal metrology processes and enhance consumer protection?",
        "options": [
            "Department of Industrial Policy and Promotion",
            "Department of Consumer Affairs",
            "Department of Economic Affairs",
            "Department of Commerce",
            "None of the Above"
        ],
        "answer": "2"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where was India's first bio-bitumen highway inaugurated?",
        "options": [
            "Delhi",
            "Mumbai",
            "Bengaluru",
            "Nagpur",
            "None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "4"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the name of the portal developed by the Department of Telecommunications to empower citizens against fraud communications and unsolicited commercial communications?",
        "options": [
            "Bharat Net Portal",
            "Sanchar Saathi Portal",
            "Sanchar Suraksha Portal",
            "Tele Safeguard Portal",
            "Sanchar Safeguard Portal"
        ],
        "answer": "2"
    },
    {
        "question": "What improvement in the Sex Ratio at Birth (SRB) of the girl child in India has been recorded under the Beti Bachao Beti Padhao scheme between 2014-15 and 2023-24?",
        "options": [
            "From 920 to 940",
            "From 918 to 930",
            "From 915 to 925",
            "From 910 to 920",
            "From 905 to 925"
        ],
        "answer": "From 918 to 930"
    },
    {
        "question": "With which country is India conducting the 4th edition of the joint military exercise HARIMAU SHAKTI in December 2024?",
        "options": [
            "Indonesia",
            "Malaysia",
            "Thailand",
            "Vietnam",
            "Myanmar"
        ],
        "answer": "2"
    },
    {
        "question": "Under which scheme has the Central Board of Direct Taxes launched the electronic campaign to address mismatches in income and transactions?",
        "options": [
            "Digital Tax Compliance Scheme, 2023",
            "Income Disclosure Initiative, 2024",
            "e-Verification Scheme, 2021",
            "Annual Information Monitoring Program",
            "Both 1 and 2"
        ],
        "answer": "e-Verification Scheme, 2021"
    },
    {
        "question": "In which state is the Adani Krishnapatnam Port, which has been granted permission to import petroleum by sea from August 28, 2024, to March 1, 2026, located?",
        "options": [
            "Tamil Nadu",
            "Odisha",
            "Gujarat",
            "Andhra Pradesh",
            "Maharashtra"
        ],
        "answer": "4"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which initiative was launched to promote Indian Sign Language (ISL) as a language and a subject?",
        "options": [
            "Bharat Digital Channel",
            "PM e-Vidya DTH 24×7 Channel",
            "ISL Learning Network",
            "Digital Bharat Education Hub",
            "None of the Above"
        ],
        "answer": "2"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which state in India received a $188.28 million loan from the World Bank to boost economic growth in backward districts?",
        "options": [
            "Gujarat",
            "Maharashtra",
            "Bihar",
            "Uttar Pradesh",
            "Madhya Pradesh"
        ],
        "answer": "2"
    },
    {
        "question": "The Linen Inspection and Sorting Assistant (LISA) system is an initiative of which organization?",
        "options": [
            "Ministry of Textile",
            "Indian Railways",
            "Ministry of Civil Aviation",
            "NITI Aayog",
            "Ministry of Consumer Affairs"
        ],
        "answer": "Indian Railways"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which initiative was launched by Dr. Jitendra Singh on Good Governance Day to strengthen Panchayati Raj Institutions?",
        "options": [
            "Prashasan Gaon Ki Aur",
            "CPGRAMS Annual Samvelan",
            "Viksit Panchayat Karmayogi",
            "Single Simplified Pension Plan",
            "None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "3"
    },
    {
        "question": "On which occasion will the government launch the Jago Grahak Jago App and Jagriti App to enhance consumer safety?",
        "options": [
            "National Consumer Day",
            "World Consumer Rights Day",
            "National Safety Day",
            "Cyber Security Day",
            "None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "National Consumer Day"
    },
    {
        "question": "As of now ( Nov 24 ) , how many accounts have been opened under the Pradhan Mantri Jan Dhan Yojana (PMJDY), and how many of them are inoperative?",
        "options": [
            "50.20 crore accounts opened, 12.50 crore inoperative",
            "54.03 crore accounts opened, 11.30 crore inoperative",
            "53.50 crore accounts opened, 10.80 crore inoperative",
            "55.00 crore accounts opened, 9.00 crore inoperative",
            "52.10 crore accounts opened, 13.00 crore inoperative"
        ],
        "answer": "54.03 crore accounts opened, 11.30 crore inoperative"
    },
    {
        "question": "Rhino reintroduction efforts have gained momentum in which wildlife sanctuary in Arunachal Pradesh?",
        "options": [
            "Namdapha National Park",
            "Dibang Wildlife Sanctuary",
            "Ering Wildlife Sanctuary",
            "Mouling National Park",
            "Pakke Tiger Reserve"
        ],
        "answer": "Ering Wildlife Sanctuary"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is India’s total external debt in 2023, as per the World Bank International Debt Report?",
        "options": [
            "$610.67 billion",
            "$635.84 billion",
            "$646.79 billion",
            "$655.74 billion",
            "$675.95 billion"
        ],
        "answer": "$646.79 billion"
    },
    {
        "question": "How many children received the Pradhan Mantri Rashtriya Bal Puraskar from President Murmu in December 2024?",
        "options": [
            "10 children",
            "17 children",
            "20 children",
            "27 children",
            "37 children"
        ],
        "answer": "17 children"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following Central Armed Police Forces celebrated its 60th raising day in December 2024?",
        "options": [
            "Central Reserve Police Force",
            "Border Security Force",
            "Sashastra Seema Bal",
            "Indo-Tibetan Border Police",
            "CISF"
        ],
        "answer": "Border Security Force"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where will the 2025 Para Athletics World Championships be hosted in India?",
        "options": [
            "Mumbai",
            "Bengaluru",
            "Delhi",
            "Hyderabad",
            "Chennai"
        ],
        "answer": "3"
    }
]